## Lucas J. Sterzinger

Curriculum Vitae

## Address removed for Public CV https://github.com/lsterzinger

#### INTEREST STATEMENT

I am an Atmospheric Science PhD candidate at UC Davis, graduating 12/2022. My research focuses on numerical modelling of clouds and precipitation processes. I am passionate about open source and open science. I am involved in the Kerchunk Python library, which makes existing cloud-hosted datasets more accessible. I want to work and do research at the intersection of geoscience, data science, and software development.

### **EDUCATION**

PhD, Atmospheric Science University of California, Davis, Davis, CA Anticipated Graduation: Fall 2022

Bachelor of Science, Atmospheric Sciences University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND

Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Aeronautics University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND 2012 - 2017

2012 - 2017

2017 - Present

### **TECHNICAL**

Languages & Software: Python, Julia, Fortran Operating Systems: Unix/Linux, MacOS, Windows Software Packages:

- PyRAMS (maintainer) Package for working with RAMS model data
- Kerchunk (contributor) Cloud performant access to NetCDF4 data

### **PUBLICATIONS**

Do Arctic mixed-phase clouds sometimes dissipate due to insufficient aerosol? Evidence from comparisons between observations and idealized simulations Sterzinger, L. J., Sedlar, J., Guy, H., Neely III, R., & Igel, A. L.

Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics

https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-22-8973-2022

The Effects of Ice Habit on Simulated Orographic Snowfall

Sterzinger, L. J., & Igel, A. L. - Journal of Hydrometeorology https://doi.org/10.1175/JHM-D-20-0253.1

Models in the Cloud: A Cost Exploration of Cloud Computing for the Atmospheric Sciences

News@Unidata Blog

https://www.unidata.ucar.edu/blogs/news/entry/models-in-the-cloud-a

2022

2021

2017

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Graduate Student Researcher

Atmospheric Science Graduate Group, UC Davis

Dr. Adele Igel, Faculty Advisor

- Works on various research related to cloud and precipitation physics. Projects include:
  - Effect of ice crystal habit (shape) on orographic snowfall in the Sierra Nevada Mountains.
     (Funding: Internal)
  - Examining the relationship between mixed-phase Arctic cloud dissipation and aerosol properties. (Funding: DOE ASR; A. Igel, PI)
  - Assessing relative impacts on aerosol contained within the boundary layer and free troposphere
    on the microphysics and other properties of Arctic mixed-phase clouds. (Funding: DOE ASR;
    A. Igel, PI)

Intern Summer 2021

Summer Internship in Parallel Computational Science (SIParCS) National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR), Boulder, CO

- Worked with Chelle Gentemann (Farallon Inst./NASA TOPS), Kevin Paul (NCAR), Julia Kent (NCAR), Rich Signell (USGS) and Martin Durant (Anaconda Inc.) on the development of the Kerchunk software library and its applicability and performance accessing cloud-hosted NOAA/NASA satellite data.
- Wrote documentation, blog posts, and example code on how to get started using Kerchunk published open-source on GitHub.

### Undergraduate Research Assistant

2016 - 2017

2017 - Present

Dept. of Atmospheric Sciences, University of N. Dakota

Dr. Gretchen Mullendore, Faculty Advisor

• Worked on the "Big Weather Web" project examining potential uses for cloud computing infrastructure for numerical weather prediction.

### Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

2015 - 2017

Dept. of Atmospheric Sciences, University of N. Dakota

• Independently taught Introduction to Meteorology lab, complete with weekly lectures and laboratory experiments.

### Technical Support Specialist

2012 - 2017

Univ. of N. Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences

• Responsible for direct technology support to faculty, staff, and students. Also worked on managing video conference sytems, networks, and servers.

### SERVICE

### UC Davis Graduate Student Association

• General Assembly Representative

2019-2022

• Elections Committee

2019-2020

UC Davis Academic Senate Committee on Information Technology	
Graduate Student Representative	2020-2021
SELECTED CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS  Open Science Success Stories Session Co-Convener American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting 2022 - Chicago, IL	Dec. 2022
Arctic Mixed-Phase Clouds Sometimes Dissipate Due to Insufficient Aerosol - Evidence from Idealized Large Eddy Simulations Oral Presentation European Geosciences Union General Assembly 2022 - Vienna, Austria	May 2022
Arctic Mixed-Phase Clouds Sometimes Dissipate due to Insufficient Aerosol: Evidence from Idealized Large Eddy Simulations Oral Presentation 2nd QuIESCENT Workshop - Tromsø, Norway	Apr. 2022
Fake it until you make it — Reading GOES NetCDF4 data on AWS S3 as Zarr for rapid data access Oral Presentation and Interactive Workshop 2022 ESIP January Meeting	Jan. 2022
Cloud-performant reading of NetCDF4/HDF5/Grib2 using the Zarr library Oral Presentation American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting 2021	Dec. 2021
Effects of Aerosol Concentration on the Dissipation of Arctic Mixed-Phase Clouds eLightning American Geophysics Union Fall Meeting 2020	Dec. 2020

# **MEMBERSHIPS**

American Meteorological Society American Geophysics Union European Geosciences Union

# LANGUAGES

English

French (Bilingual Fluency)